export const historyyear9qs = [
  {
    question: "American Revolution: When was the American Revoluntionary War?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(1775)ANDCONTAINS(1783)",
    help: "The American Revoluntionary War lasted from 1775 to 1783",
  },
  {
    question: "American Revolution: When was the Britain Stamp Act passed?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(1765)",
    help: "1765 Britain passed the stamp Act that put a stamp duty tax on various documents and items",
  },
  {
    question: "American Revolution: What happened in 1767?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(TOWNSHEND)ANDCONTAINS(ACTS)",
    help: "Townshend Acts - Britain introduced more new taxes",
  },
  {
    question: "American Revolution: What happened in 1773?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(TEA)",
    help: "Tea Duty - Britain introduced a tea duty",
  },
  {
    question: "French Revolution: When was the French revolution?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(1789)ANDCONTAINS(1799)",
    help: "The French Revolution lasted 10 years from 1789 to 1799",
  },
  {
    question: "French Revolution: What date did the French revolution start?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(14)ANDCONTAINS(JUL)ANDCONTAINSTHREE(1789)",
    help: "The French Revolution began on July 14 1789 when revoluntionaries stormed Bastille prison",
  },
  {
    question: "French Revolution: What year did the French revolution end?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(1799)",
    help: "The French Revolution ended in 1799 when Napoleon established the French Consulate",
  },
  {
    question: "What happened in 1917?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(RUSSIAN)ANDCONTAINS(REVOLUTION)",
    help: "Russian Revolution, on 24 Feb, riots broke out in St Petersburg. People were angry because there was little food and World War I was going badly",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Russian Revolution: For 300 years, Russia had been ruled by a royal family - the ________?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(ROMANOVS)",
    help: "Romanovs",
  },
  {
    question: "Russian Revolution: What is a queen tsar known as?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(TSARINA)",
    help: "Tsarina",
  },
  {
    question: "Russian Revolution: What is a tsar?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(RULER)",
    help: "A tsar is a ruler of Russia, similar to a king. It comes from the Roman word caesar",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Russian Revolution: Who was the ruler at the time before the revolution?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(TSAR)ANDCONTAINS(NICHOLAS)ANDCONTAINSTHREE(II)",
    help: "Tsar Nicholas II",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Russian Revolution: Who took over ruling after Tsar Nicholas II stepped down?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(PROVISIONAL)ANDCONTAINS(GOVERNMENT)",
    help: "A group of people called the provisional government",
  },
  {
    question: "Russian Revolution: What happened in October?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(REVOLUTION)ANDCONTAINSOR(SECOND_2ND)",
    help: "A second revolution",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Russian Revolution: What political system happened from the second revolution?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(COMMUNISM)",
    help: "Communism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Russian Revolution: Who was the first communist ruler of Russia?",
    answer: "CONTAINS(VLADIMIR)ANDCONTAINS(LENIN)",
    help: "Vladimir Lenin",
  },
];
